{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Yield coefficient represents", "opta": "total biomass or product produced", "optb": "conversion efficiency of a substrate into product", "optc": "conversion rate of a substrate into biomass or product", "optd": "production time of biomass or product", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lowest biomass yield in a culture of Escherichia coli will be in", "opta": "an aerated batch culture containing a initial high concentration of glucose", "optb": "an aerated batch reactor containing an initial low concentration of glucose", "optc": "an aerated fed-batch reactor having a low glucose concentration", "optd": "an aerated continuous reactor having a low glucose concentration", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When two populations compete for a single growth limiting substrate in a continuous fermenter, which organism would not be washed out?", "opta": "Organism maintaining the highest substrate concentration", "optb": "Organism maintaining the lowest substrate concentration", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Organism maintaining the moderate substrate concentration", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The continuous cultures are not widely used in industry because", "opta": "they are not suited for the production of secondary metabolites", "optb": "contamination or mutation can have a disastrous effect on the operation", "optc": "the government will not approve the licensing of pharmaceuticals produced in continuous cultures", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lowest yield of ATP /is in", "opta": "fermentation", "optb": "aerobic respiration", "optc": "anaerobic respiration", "optd": "same in (a), (b) and (c)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mixing in an anaerobic sludge blanket reactor is due to", "opta": "rapid change in water temperatures throughout the reactor", "optb": "release of gases by the microbial populations", "optc": "swimming of microbes", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In batch culture, protogon is produced from peptone during the stationary phase with a yield of 0.4 protogon mg per g of peptone. If it is to be produced in a chemostat at a dilution rate of 0.5 h-1 from a medium containing 10 g.l-1 of peptone, then the rate of protogon synthesis would be", "opta": "0 g.l-1h-1", "optb": "0.5 g.l-1h-1", "optc": "1 g.l-1h-1", "optd": "2 g.l-1h-1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Formation of end product by Lactococcus lactis will become non-growth associated as lactic acid accumulates because", "opta": "cells will redirect ATP to anabolism", "optb": "cells will redirect NAD+ to anabolism", "optc": "cells will redirect ATP to facilitate the diffusion of lactic acid and H+ out of the cells", "optd": "cells will redirect ATP to the active transport of lactic acid and H+ out of the cells", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following would not be subjected to the \"glucose effect\"?", "opta": "Aspergillus fumigatus", "optb": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae", "optc": "Escherichia coli", "optd": "Aspergillus niger", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Immobilized cell reactors for wastewater treatment have the advantage of having/being", "opta": "higher cell concentration", "optb": "more stable and prevent washout", "optc": "higher dilution rate before the cells washout", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the statement is true for continuous reactor at steady state?", "opta": "The rates of biomass, substrate and product concentrations are zero", "optb": "Biomass, substrate and product concentrations are zero", "optc": "Biomass, substrate and product concentrations do not change with time", "optd": "Biomass, substrate and product concentrations change with time", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A continuous bioreactor in which only the flow rate is used to control the rate of cell or product productivity is called", "opta": "turbidostat", "optb": "chemostat", "optc": "level stat", "optd": "pH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For organisms growing in a chemostat, the specific growth rate", "opta": "cannot be determined", "optb": "can be determined from the dilution rate", "optc": "equals to the maximum specific growth rate of the culture", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae is being grown in a chemostat converts glucose to biomass, ethanol, glycerol and carbon dioxide. At steady state, the concentration of glucose, biomass, ethanol and glycerol will", "opta": "decrease with time", "optb": "increase with time", "optc": "be constant", "optd": "change randomly with time", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In aerobic yeast fermentation for production of citric acid from alkanes using a fed-batch culture, why alkanes are slowly fed to the yeast?", "opta": "Citric acid is toxic to the cells", "optb": "Alkanes cause foaming", "optc": "Fast addition of alkanes will inhibit the cells and reduce oxygen transfer rates", "optd": "Fast addition of alkanes will cause the cells to grow too quickly", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A continuous reactor has a dilution rate of 0.5 h-1. Its residence time would be", "opta": "ln(2)/0.5", "optb": "ln(2) x 0.5", "optc": "0.5 h", "optd": "2 h", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used to calculate mass of substrate in the reactor?", "opta": "Flow rate x substrate concentration in the reactor", "optb": "Volume of reactor x substrate concentration in reactor", "optc": "Flow rate x mass of reactor", "optd": "Volume of reactor x Flow rate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If biomass yields are constant, then the biomass productivity of a culture grown in continuous reactor will", "opta": "always decrease with dilution rate", "optb": "increase with dilution rate until washout", "optc": "remain constant irrespective of the dilution rate", "optd": "decrease with dilution rate until washout", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Low dissolved oxygen concentrations leads to", "opta": "low biomass yields", "optb": "high biomass yields", "optc": "no effect on biomass yields", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a continuous reactor, the medium contains 40 g.l-1 of maltose and the medium flow rate is 10 litres per hour and the effluent contains 20 g.l-l of lactate. What is the productivity of lactate production from this reactor?", "opta": "50 g maltose.l-1", "optb": "50 g lactate.l-1", "optc": "200 g maltose.l-1", "optd": "200 g lactate.l-1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fed-batch reactor containing 1 g.l-1 of substrate in 2 litre of medium. It is fed with 1 g.l-l of substrate at the rate of 1 litre per hour. After 10 hours, the concentration of substrate in the reactor was 0.5 g.l-1 . The mass of substrate that was used by the culture in the reactor was", "opta": "2g", "optb": "6g", "optc": "8g", "optd": "12g", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Toxins accumulated in a reactor can lead to low biomass yields probably due to which of the following?", "opta": "NAD+ is diverted away from homeostasis to anabolism", "optb": "ATP is diverted away from homeostasis to anabolism", "optc": "NAD+ is diverted away from anabolism to homeostasis", "optd": "ATP is diverted away from anabolism to homeostasis", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cellular productivity in a continuous stirred tank fermenter (CSTF) increases with an increase in the dilution rate and reaches a maximum value. If the dilution rate is increased beyond the maximum point, the productivity will", "opta": "decrease abruptly", "optb": "increase", "optc": "increase drastically", "optd": "be zero", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fluidized bed bioreactors provide higher mass transfer rates than packed bed bioreactors because", "opta": "mixing is higher in fluidized bed bioreactors", "optb": "particles move with the fluid in a fluidized bed bioreactor", "optc": "immobilized particles are smaller in the fluidized bed bioreactors", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In fed-batch fermentation, mass of substrate utilized is calculated using the relationship", "opta": "initial mass of substrate in the reactor + final mass of substrate in the reactor + flow rate x [substrate in the feed]", "optb": "initial mass of substrate in the reactor - final mass of substrate in the reactor + flow rate x [substrate in the feed]", "optc": "initial mass of substrate in the reactor + final mass of substrate in the reactor - flow rate x [substrate in the feed]", "optd": "initial mass of substrate in the reactor + final mass of substrate in the reactor - flow rate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A chemostat has a liquid volume of 2 litres and is being fed at a rate of 4 litres per hour. Dilution rate for this reactor will be", "opta": "2 litres", "optb": "2 litres per hour", "optc": "2 h-1", "optd": "4 litres per hour", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mixing per unit volume is observed to be poorest in", "opta": "continuous packed bed reactor", "optb": "continuous fluidized bed bioreactor", "optc": "continuous airlift bioreactor", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The growth of an organism on glucose is described by the following Monod model parameters: \u03bcm = 0.5 h-1 and Ks =0.1 g.l-1, if the concentration of glucose in the feed is 10 g.l-1 and the dilution rate is set to 0.4 h-1, then the steady state concentration of glucose in the effluent will be", "opta": "0 g.l-1", "optb": "0.5 g.l-1", "optc": "1.0 g.l-1", "optd": "10 g.l-1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A continuous reactor at steady state contains 0.04 g.l-1 of biomass and 0.02 g.l-1 of phenol. The feed contained 0.1 g.l-1 of phenol. The biomass yield would be", "opta": "0.4 g.g-1", "optb": "0.5 g.g-1", "optc": "1.0 g.g-1", "optd": "5.0 g.g-1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A culture system with constant environmental conditions maintained through continual provision of nutrient and removal of wastes is called __________ culture system.", "opta": "continuous", "optb": "batch", "optc": "fed-batch", "optd": "semi continuous", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main reason for production of antibiotics in fed batch reactors is", "opta": "the presence of precursors is often toxic to the cells", "optb": "higher yields when cells enter the stationary phase", "optc": "higher yields when cell growth slows", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fed batch reactors is used to produce vinegar because", "opta": "it can maintain low ethanol concentrations", "optb": "it can maintain low acetic acid concentrations", "optc": "acetic acid bacteria tend to ferment at high ethanol concentrations", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a culture of fermenting yeast becomes metabolically uncoupled, ethanol", "opta": "becomes a secondary metabolite", "optb": "production becomes growth associated", "optc": "production becomes non-growth associated", "optd": "becomes a growth nutrient", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mixing profiles closest to plug flow are observed in", "opta": "continuous packed bed reactor", "optb": "stirred tank reactor with biomass recycles", "optc": "continuous fluidized bed bioreactor", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On a glucose medium, the growth of an organism is characterized by the following Monod model and stoichiometric parameters \u03bcm = 0.3 h-1, Ks =0.05 g.l-1 and Yxs = 0.3 g.g-1 When this organism is grown in a 2 litre continuous on a medium containing 10 g.l-1 of glucose added at 1 l.h-1, the steady state concentration of biomass in the reactor will be", "opta": "0 g.l-1", "optb": "0.4 g.l-1", "optc": "0.5 g.l-1", "optd": "10 g.l-1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Unsteady state mass balance for dynamic model of continuous stirred tank reactor (CSTR) is", "opta": "time rate of total amount in rector = rate of addition to reactor -rate of removal + rate of formation", "optb": "total amount in rector = rate of addition to reactor - rate of removal + rate of formation", "optc": "rate of total amount in rector = rate of addition to reactor - rate of removal + rate of formation", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fed-batch reactor initially contains 2 litre of medium. If it was fed at 1 litre per hour, then after 10 hours, the volume of the reactor will be", "opta": "1 litre", "optb": "2 litre", "optc": "3 litre", "optd": "13 litre", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A Bacillus sp. produces an antibiotic only during the stationary phase when grown in a batch culture. If grown in a 5 litre continuous culture, the steady state productivity of the antibiotic", "opta": "will increase until the culture washes out", "optb": "will decrease after washout", "optc": "will be zero", "optd": "will be infinite", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a fluidized bed reactor, the function of the disengagement zone is to", "opta": "reduce loss of particles from the reactor", "optb": "reduce the velocity of the particles near the surface of the reactor", "optc": "reduce foaming problems", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae produces high biomass yields at low glucose concentrations and high dissolved oxygen concentrations. Which of the following should be followed for maximizing its biomass productivity?", "opta": "Batch fermenter with a high initial glucose concentration", "optb": "Continuous fermenter with a low initial glucose concentration", "optc": "Fed batch fermenter", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}